Software Engineer

Iowa City, Iowa

Experienced full stack software engineer with a proven record of delivering software on multiple platforms. Adaptable and reliable problem solver who can acquire the necessary skills to accomplish development goals.

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

Backend Development: Web content and service development on multiple platforms (Node.js, C#, Java, PHP, Ruby, Python). API design and implementation. OAuth2 and OpenID Connect implementation and integration.

Frontend Development: JavaScript development throughout entire career. Single page web application development in React+Redux and Backbone.js. Extensive experience with jQuery. Exposure to AngularJS from improving and maintaining legacy web apps.

Data Management and Exchange: Relational, document, and index data stores including PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, RavenDB, and Lucene (Zend Lucene). HTTP, JSON, and XML. Minor experience with RabbitMQ and Protocol Buffers.

Tools and Processes: Git and GitHub. JIRA, Pivotal Tracker, Trello, Mantis, and Bugzilla. CircleCl, TeamCity, and Jenkins. Agile, Pair/Mob Programming, TDD.

PROJECTS

| Firefox Screenshots Mozilla | Full-stack JavaScript development including a Firefox addon, a React web frontend with server-side rendering, and an Express server. Continuous Integration with CircleCI. Selenium driven browser addon testing. |
|--|---|
| Auth Server InComm Digital Solutions | OAuth2 implementation with Katana to authorize internal and external web APIs. User management web application in React+Redux. |
| Yesmail Enterprise 8 Yesmail | Full frontend rewrite in Backbone.js and React. Implementation and integration of OpenID Connect. A new feature to enable users to easily schedule and target emails in a visual if-this-then-that fashion. |
| Construction Contractor and Consultant Retainer Program Oregon University System | Digital application and approval process with PDF generation and signed application upload. Approved contractors and consultants indexed with Zend Lucene and searchable through a web UI. |
| Campus Map Oregon State University | Dynamic campus map built with Google Maps API (v1) and MySQL spatial extensions. Map layer tile image generation using PHP GD2 and ImageMagick. Map data indexed with and searched through Zend Lucene. |

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Test Pilot Engineer – Firefox Screenshots (Contract)

Remote

October 2017 – Present

- Implemented new features and bug fixes for the Firefox Screenshots addon and its web site
- Refactored the Screenshots annotations editor and added features such as undo/redo and text

- Integrated the Screenshots service with an external API to detect offensive images
- Participated in efforts to migrate Screenshots from a legacy addon to a browser extension
- Increased addon testing with Selenium tests
- Migrated Firefox Screenshots to CircleCl 2.0

InComm Digital Solutions Software Engineer

Portland, OR

April 2016 - June 2017

- Implemented an OAuth2 service using Katana along with a user management web application in React and Redux
- Improved and maintained digital gift card web applications
- Participated in workgroup to establish and improve automated web API testing tools and process
- Contributed to internationalization effort by updating web front ends, web services, and database columns and stored procedures

Yesmail

Portland, OR

June 2012 – April 2016

Software Engineer

 Worked closely with Product Managers to introduce new features to Yesmail's flagship web application through full stack development, including Java based RESTful APIs and a Google Web Toolkit frontend

- Participated in the development of the next generation frontend with Backbone is and React
- Created a visual marketing campaign builder to simplify email scheduling and audience targeting
- Improved the web application's "Click Map" by making it attractive and printable
- Implemented and integrated OpenID Connect for single sign-on authentication

Central Web Services, Oregon State University Lead Web Application Developer

Corvallis, OR July 2008 – June 2012

- Designed, developed, and maintained web applications in a Linux+Apache+MySQL+PHP/Ruby on Rails environment
- Participated in all stages of the software development lifecycle, including requirement gathering, database schema design, full stack development, and code reviews
- Delegated work to and assisted student and junior developers

Web Application Developer

June 2004 - July 2008

- Led the OSU Campus Map project, creating a dynamic, searchable map utilizing Google Maps API,
 CakePHP, Zend Lucene, and MySQL spatial extensions
- Developed a survey builder to allow university students and staff to set up online surveys with anonymous or optional authenticated participation
- Built Drupal modules and wrote Python installation and update scripts for Drupal instance management
- Integrated web applications with OSU's payment gateway to accept credit card payments
- Developed and enhanced LAMP based web applications

Mozilla

Remote

Part-Time Contract Developer

June 2010 - Nov 2011

- Fixed bugs and implemented features for the Django powered addons.mozilla.org
- Fixed security issues for getpersonas.com
- Performed code reviews via GitHub pull requests

EDUCATION

Oregon State University
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Cum Laude

Corvallis, OR Sept 2000 – June 2004